Guide to the Deane W. Malott papers, 1951-1964
Malott, Deane W. papers, 1951-1964
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Deane W. Malott papers, 1951-1964.
3-9-651
Deane W. (Deane Waldo) Malott, 1898-
31.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, office files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Deane W. Malott Papers consist of correspondence and office files deriving from his presidency of Cornell University from 1951 to 1963.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Deane Waldo Malott was born in Abilene, Kansas on 10 July 1898. He received a bachelor's degree from the University of Kansas in 1921, and a master's degree from the Harvard Business School in 1923. From 1923 to 1929 he was assistant dean of the Harvard Business School; from 1929 to 1933 he was vice president of the Hawaiian Pineapple Company; and from 1933 to 1939 he was an associate professor at the Harvard Business School. Malott was Chancellor of the University of Kansas from 1939 until 1951, when he became the sixth president of Cornell University, a position he held until 1963.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Deane W. Malott Papers consist of correspondence and office files deriving from his presidency of Cornell University from 1951 to 1963, pertaining to the routine operation of the university from the President's Office. A small part of the collection consists of the social correspondence of President Malott during his years in office, and is concerned mainly with his travel, autograph collection, and letters to and from friends. Subjects include the relations between the Malott administration and the Board of Trustees, and correspondence between Malott and individual members of the Board, members of the Cornell University Council, and with patron donors of the university. Another major focus of the collection is the administration's dealings with the university's colleges, divisions, and departments, with the many standing and ad hoc committees within the university, with the State University of New York, and with the New York State and federal government departments and agencies. University departments or divisions appearing most prominently in the collection, and topics affiliated with them include the Cornell University Library, the development of its special collections, and the construction of Olin Library; the Department of Physical Education and Athletics and the expansion of its programs and facilities; and the Cornell University Medical College including the question of an enrollment quota for Jewish applicants.
Also, the University Faculty pertaining especially to issues of academic freedom; the Dept. of Economics including the controversy engendered by some alumni concerning the alleged lack of a traditional capitalist perspective. Topics also include the Graduate School of Nutrition, the Social Science Research Center, the School of Hotel Administration, Cornell United Religious Work, ROTC, the Law School, Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, the College of Arts and Sciences, the College of Architecture, the College of Engineering, the Graduate School of Business and Public Administration, the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, the New York State College of Agriculture, the New York State College of Home Economics, and the New York State Veterinary College. There are also files documenting the searches for and appointments of deans of the School of Hotel Administration, the Law School, the College of Architecture, and the Graduate School of Business and Public Administration. Other special concerns documented in the collection include the expansion of university research, the Office of University Development, the increased attention paid to alumni affairs, and the construction of Olin Library, Gannett Clinic, Collyer Boathouse, Helen Neweman Hall, and other buildings and facilities. Another emphasis in the collection is the administration's relations with corporations and business enterprises, and with educational and philanthropic foundations.
These include the Rockefeller Foundation, the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, the Ford Foundation, the National Science Foundation, the American Association of Land Grant Colleges and State Universities, and the American Council on Education. A significant topic in the collection is communism and the discord of the McCarthy Era, including the fears of alumni, social critics, and newspaper editorialists concerning the supposed influence of the communist ethic in the teaching of some members of the faculty, with specific reference to Philip Morrison, Marcus Singer, Harry Steinmetz, and Paul Sweezy. The question becomes one of academic freedom and Malott's defense of his faculty is well documented. Another main topic is student deportment, and the new customs evident on campus among the student body. The social problem of fraternities is chronicled, pertaining chiefly to drinking and male-female relationships; the question of fraternities with restrictive clauses and racially segregated sororities is also evidenced in the collection. Another issue is the controversy over University rules regarding the the presence of women in men's off-campus apartments, which led in part to a major demonstration in 1958. A small amount of material pertains to sex discrimination. Other issues include the founding and chairing of the John L. Senior Professorship, and the affiliations drawn among the Ivy League schools.
Topics also include cooperative programs with other colleges, and with universities in Latin America, Europe, and Africa; also, relations with Ithaca, N. Y., the development of educational television, and the Liberian Codification Project. Includes notes by William Rees Sears on the selection of Malott as President. Major correspondents include Neal Dow Becker, Walter S. Carpenter, John Lyon Collyer, Arthur H. Dean, Mary H. Donlon, Victor Emanuel, Caroline Werner Gannett, Frank E. Gannett, Larry E. Gubb, Eugene F. Kaufman, Philip Morrison, William I. Myers, Jansen Noyes, Nicholas H. Noyes, John M. Olin, Nelson A. Rockefeller, George H. Rockwell, Francis H. Scheetz, Maxwell M. Upson, Harry V. Wade, and J. Carlton Ward.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Malott, Deane W. (Dean Waldo), 1898-; Becker, Neal Dow.; Carpenter, Walter S.; Cisler, Walter L.; Collyer, John L.; Dean, Arthur H.; Donlon, Mary H., 1893-1977.; Emanuel, Victor.; Gannett, Caroline Werner, 1894-1979.; Gannett, Frank E. (Frank Ernest), 1876-1957.; Grumman, Leroy.; Gubb, Larry E.; Kahn, Alfred E. (Alfred Edward); Kaufmann, Eugene M.; Morrison, Philip.; Olin, John M.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979.; Scheetz, Francis H.; Sears, William Rees.; Singer, Marcus.; Steinmetz, Harry.; Sweezy, Paul Marlor, 1910-; Tuller, Jesse D.; Upson, Maxwell M.; Wade, Harry V.; Ward, J. Carlton.; Alfred P. Sloan Foundation.; American Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities.; American Council on Education.; Andrew Dickson White Museum of Art.; Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory.; Cornell University--Admissions.; Cornell University--Administration.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Finance.; Cornell University--Funds and scholarships.; Cornell University--Libraries.; Cornell University--Museums.; Cornell University--Presidents.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University--Alumni and alumnae.; Cornell University Library.; Cornell University Medical College.; Cornell University. Dept. of Economics.; Cornell University.; Cornell University. Dept. of Physical Education and Athletics.; Cornell University. University Faculty.; Ford Foundation.; Ivy League.; National Science Foundation.; New York (State). State Education Dept.; New York State College of Agriculture--Administration.; New York State College of Home Economics--Administration.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations--Administration.; Rockefeller Foundation.; State University of New York.; United States. Army. Reserve Officers' Training Corps.; University of the State of New York.
Subjects:
Academic freedom.; Sex discrimination.; Communism in education.; College students--Conduct of life.; Greek letter societies.; Land grants for education.; Military education.; University cooperation.; College administrators.; College presidents.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Presidental administration papers, 1951-1963
1951-1953
Box 1, Folder 1 through Box 10, Folder 1
1953-1955
Box 10, Folder 2 through Box 17, Folder 5
1955-1957
Box 17, Folder 6 through Box 21, Folder 31
1957-1959
Box 21, Folder 32 through Box 26, Folder 58
1959-1961
Box 26, Folder 59 through Box 28, Folder 74
1961-1963
Box 28, Folder 75 through Box 29, Folder 95
Series II. Dean W. Malott correspondence, 1951-1963
Box 30, Folders 1-94
Series III. Reports and annual reports
Box 31, Folder 1 through Box 33, Folder 15
CONTAINER LIST
- A Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Abbe, Elfriede; Stassen, Harold E.; Budenz, Louis Francis; Wright, C. 0.; Rumely, Edward A. Americans Will Vote, Inc.; Communism.
- A Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Willcox, Bertram F.; Abbe, Elfriede. Communism; American Institute of Pacific Relations.
- American Council on Education., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  Adams, Arthur S. Military training.
- American Institute of Management., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- American Institute of Pacific Relations., 1952-53 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Holland, William L.; de Grassi, Antonio.
- American Universities Field Staff, Inc. Talbot, Phillips., 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- American Council of Learned Societies., 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Adams, Henry H.
- America's Future, Inc., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Flynn, John T.
- Applications for Jobs., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 11-14)
- United States Army., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Associated Universities, Inc., 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Berkner, Lloyd V.
- Association of American Colleges., 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Snavely, Guy E.
- Association of American Universities., 1950-53 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Baruch, Bernard M.; Wriston, Henry M.
- Association of Colleges and Universities of the State of New York., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Ingalls, Lester W.
- Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Thackrey, Russell I.
- Atlantic Union., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- B Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Janeway, Eliot.
- C Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Emerson, Willard I.; Wetzsteon, Ross. Communism.
- C Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Antell, Bert W. Committee for a Free Asia.
- C Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Antell, Bert W.; Koutouzas, Leo. Academic freedom.
- C Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Hottel, Althea K. Commission on the Education of Women.
- Carnegie Corporation., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Gardner, John W.; Sharp, Lauriston.
- Civil Defense., 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- D Miscellaneous., 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  de Kiewiet, Cornelius W.
- E Miscellaneous. Davidson, Carter., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Edmund Ezra Day., 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Economic Cooperation Administration., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Myers, William I.; White, Egbert.
- F Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Leach, Henry Goddard; Berry, Romeyn; Debye, Peter. Fashions Unlimited; Fiske Icelandic Collection.
- Federation of Cornell Men's and Women's Clubs., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- United States Office of Education, Higher Education Publications., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- United States Office of Education., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Federal Security Agency.
- United States Dept. of Agriculture., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Federal Government, Letters to Congressmen., 1950-52 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Ives, Irving M.; Schurman, Jacob Gould.
- United States Dept. of State., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Gallman, Waldemar J.
- United States Government General Correspondence., 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Military Preparedness., [1941] 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Rogalsky, George F. United States Selective Service System.
- United States Selective Service System., 1948-53 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Ford Foundation Research Project in India., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Opler, Morris E.; Hoffman, Paul G.
- Ford Foundation., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 44-46)
  Fund for the Advancement of Education.
- G Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  Gannett, Frank E.; Pew, Joseph N.; Buckley, William F. DWM Inaugural Address; Yale University.
- General Electric Electronics Laboratory., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  Wright, Theodore P.; Oldfield, H. R. General Electric Company; Savage Tract.
- H Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  Hauser, Ernst A.; Hancher, Virgil M. Rhodes Scholarships.
- Honorary Degrees Miscellaneous., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- I Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  Hancher, Virgil M. International Association of Universities.
- India-American Conference., 1952-53 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  American Institute of Pacific Relations.
- Income Taxes., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  Emerson, Willard I.
- Institute of Current World Affairs. Rogers, Walter S., 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Institute of International Education., 1952-53 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  Holland, Kenneth.
- Ithaca, New York., 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  Shaw, Stanley C.; Treman, Robert E.
- Ithaca College., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  Job, Leonard B.
- J Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  Jessup, Philip C.; Janeway, Eliot.
- K Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  Kerner, Robert J.
- L Miscellaneous., 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  Lodge, Henry Cabot; Emerson, Willard I.; Kerr, A. E. Province of Nova Scotia.
- M Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Upson, Maxwell M.; MacArthur, Douglas. Miami (Ohio) University; Massachusetts Institute of Technology; Communism.
- M Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  McConnell, James A.; Morris, Evan J. Communism.
- M Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Maxwell Vacation School.
- Middle States Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Nyquist, Ewald B.
- N Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  National Scholarship Service and Fund for Negro Students.
- N Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  National University Extension Association; National Scholarship Service and Fund for Negro Students; National Republican Club.
- N Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  National Thrift Committee.
- N Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Emanuel, Victor. National Education Association; Czechoslovakia; National Industrial Conference Board; NATO.
- National Association of Manufacturers., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Buck, Harry E. Committee for Free Men.
- National Association of State Universities., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Jorgensen, Albert N.
- National Commission on Accrediting., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 11-15)
- National Industrial Conference Board., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Sinclair, John S.; Becker, Neal Dow.
- United States Navy., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Naval ROTC.
- Association of NROTC Colleges., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Newcomen Society., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Collyer, John L.
- New York State Citizens Council., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Hoffman, Paul G.; Mial, H. Curtis. Ford Foundation.
- National Emergency Bulletins., 1948 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Requests for National Emergency Deferments., 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
- National Emergency Manpower., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Military Service, Printed Matter., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Military Service Correspondence., 1948-50 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Gibbs, R. C.; Howes, Raymond F.; Rogalsky, George F. Selective Service.
- Military Service Miscellaneous., 1942-50 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  Adelmann, Howard B.
- Military Service, Mimeos and Notices., 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- National Emergency Student Deferment., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- P Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  Emery, DeWitt.
- Plaques and Inscriptions., 1951-52 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Day, Edmund Ezra; Wright, Theodore P.; Williams, Emmons L.; Bailey, Liberty Hyde; Gage, Susanna Phelps. Sage Chapel; Edmund Ezra Day Hall.
- National Emergency., 1948-51 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- National Emergency Miscellaneous., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Military Service, Reserves Survey., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- O Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  Olin, John M.; Niebuhr, Reinhold; Baker, John C.
- Joseph N. Pew, Jr., 1949-52 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  Pew Memorial Trust.
- Q Miscellaneous., 1952 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  Quartermaster Association.
- Questionnaires., 1952 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Questionnaires., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- R Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  Robertson, F. E.
- Recommendations., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Rockefeller Foundation., 1951-52 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  Willets, Joseph H.
- Rockefeller Foundation Grants., 1952 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Rockefeller Foundation Reports., 1952-53 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- 8 Miscellaneous., 1950-53 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  Gallagher, Barrett.
- S Miscellaneous., 1950-53 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Shackleton's Point., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  Brown, Charles S.
- T Miscellaneous., 1949-53 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  Treman, Allan H.; Taylor, Myron C.
- Tapestries and Woodwork., 1947-53 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  Green, Norvin H.; Close, Henry B.
- TIAA (Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association)., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- TIAA (Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association)., 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Teagle Foundation., 1950-53 (Box 2, Folder 52-55)
  Teagle, Walter C.; Mott, Frank E. Berea College.
- UNESCO - International Conferences at Utrecht, Nice., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- United Nations Miscellaneous., 1952-53 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Rope, Frederick T.
- U Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  United Nations; United States Steel Corporation.
- V Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Vinson, Jack R.
- W Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Willcox, Walter F.; Dyett, H. T.; Niebuhr, Reinhold. World Student Service Fund; Wells College.
- W Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Willcox, Walter F.; Treman, Allan H.
- Watamull Foundation., 1952 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  White, William R.
- World Assembly of Youth., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- XYZ Miscellaneous., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Upson, Maxwell M.; Zinsmaster, Harry W.; Young, Fred W.
- Statutes and By-laws of the University., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Emanuel, Victor; Gubb, Larry E.; Becker, Neal Dow. Princeton University; Northwestern University; New York Foundation Seed Stocks Cooperative; Goucher College.
- Board of Trustees., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Marcham, Fred G.; Becker, Neal Dow; Emanuel, Victor; Gubb, Larry E.; Grohmann, H. Victor; Ward, J. Carlton; Taylor, Myron C.; Houtchens, Lawrence H.
- Board of Trustees., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Emanuel, Victor; Becker, Neal Dow; Taylor, Myron C.; Rockwell, George H.; Upson, Maxwell M.; Parke, John S.; Gannett, Frank E.
- Board of Trustees., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Emanuel, Victor; Carey, William D. P.; Becker, Neal Dow; Taylor, Myron C.; Dean, Arthur H.
- Board of Trustees., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Collyer, John L.; Pew, Joseph N.; Noyes, Nicholas H.; Emanuel, Victor; Upson, Maxwell M.; Newman, Floyd R.
- Board of Trustees., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Gannett, Frank E.; Emanuel, Victor; Root, E. Merrill; Becker, Neal Dow; Pew, Joseph N.; Beneway, Frank W.; Treman, Robert E.; Upson, Maxwell M.
- Board of Trustees., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Emanuel, Victor; Becker, Neal Dow; 01 in, John M.; Requardt, Gustav J.; Gannett, Frank E.; Ward, J. Carlton; Grohmann, H. Victor. Yale University.
- Board of Trustees., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Grohmann, H. Victor; Emanuel, Victor; Collyer, John L.; Upson, Maxwell M.; Ward, J. Carlton.
- Board of Trustees., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Emanuel, Victor; Ward, J. Carlton; Taylor, Myron C.; Teagle, Walter C.; Johnson, Herbert F.; Gannett, Frank E.; Wilcox, Walter F.
- Membership on the Board of Trustees., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Actions Taken by the Board of Trustees. Upson, Maxwell M., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Board of Trustees - Executive Committee. Meigs, Robert B.; Treman, Allan H., 1951-52 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Agendas for Meetings., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Board of Trustees - Investment Committee., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Board of Trustees - Buildings and Grounds Committee. Parke, John S., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 24-26)
- Board of Trustees - Law Committee., 1951-52 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Board of Trustees Board Membership Committee., 1951-52 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Trustee-Faculty Committee on Fine Arts., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Board of Trustees Sub-Committee on Finance., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  Dean, Arthur H.; Mackesey, Thomas W.; Upson, Maxwell M.
- Library Board., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  McCarthy, Stephen A.
- Committee on Physical Education and Athletics., 1952-53 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Board on Student Health and Hygiene., 1952 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Moore, Norman S.
- Administrative Board for the School of Nutrition., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Board of Governors for Willard Straight Hall., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  Coffin, Foster M,
- Councils, Advisory Councils for State Colleges., 1952 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- College of Engineering Council., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  Ward, J. Carlton.
- Council for the New York State College of Agriculture and Experiment Station., 1952-53 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  Myers, William I.
- Council for the New York State Veterinary College., 1952-53 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  Hagan, William A.
- Council for the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  Catherwood, Martin P.
- Architectural-Engineering Advisory Council., 1951-52 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- The President and the Presidency., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  Becker, Neal Dow; Johnson, Herbert F.; Alexander, Robert E.
- The President and the Presidency., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  Washburn, Kenneth. DWM Inaugural Address.
- The President and the Presidency., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  Treman, Robert E.; Dorf, Philip; MacDaniels, Laurence H.; Griff is, Stanton; Rockwell, George H. President's Office filing system.
- Deane W. Malott Inauguration., 1951-52 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  Hancher, Virgil M.; Howes, Raymond F.; Treman, Robert E.
- Deane W. Malott Inauguration., 1951-52 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  Emanuel, Victor; Schurman, Jacob Gould; Cushman, Robert E.
- Deane W. Malott Inauguration., 1951-52 (Box 3, Folder 47-48)
- President's House., 1951-52 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  Johnson, Herbert F.; Wright, Frank Lloyd.
- Deane W. Malott, Speeches and Correspondence., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  Harvill, Richard A. Ohio University; University of Arizona; Marshall College.
- Deane W. Malott, Speeches and Correspondence., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  Harvill, Richard A.; Linowitz, Sol M.; Monsees, Anita; Case, Everett; Mott, Rodney L. California Manufacturers Association.
- Deane W. Malott, Speeches and Correspondence., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  Healy, James A. National Thrift Committee.
- President - Inventory of Office., 1944-52 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Deans' Conferences., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Office of Public Relations and Information., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  Brossman, W. Robert; Heinicke, Arthur J.; Wyman, Phillips; Wright, J. Handly. Football and academics in the Ivy League.
- Office of Public Relations and Information., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  Brossman, W. Robert; Grohmann, H. Victor; Pendray, G. Edward; Dudley, Pendleton.
- Communism Miscellaneous., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  Dean, Daniel.
- Academic Freedom, Correspondence., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  Cushman, Robert E.; Parke, John S.; Deitch, Joseph; Emanuel, Victor. United States House of Representatives Committee on Un-American Activities.
- Academic Freedom, Clippings, etc., 1951-53 (Box 3, Folder 59)